Susan Caperna Lloyd collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Susan Caperna Lloyd collection 1961-2020
AFC 2018/064
Lloyd, Susan Caperna
approximately 18,210 items
59 containers
6.4 linear feet
1 text file: digital; txt
22 sound cassettes: analog
1 sound disc: analog; 7 in.
72 videocassettes (Betacam): analog
32 videocassettes (Betacam SP): analog
22 videocassettes (VHS): analog
6 videocassettes (VHS-C): analog
1 videocassette (U-matic video): analog
20 videocassettes (Hi 8): analog
1 film reel (1 in.): analog
1 videocassette (MiniDV): digital
7 video discs (DVD): digital; 4 3/4 in.
23 video files: digital, ifo, vob, mov, mp4
424 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 120 mm
2,185 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 35 mm
21 photographs: film negatives, black and white; 4 x 5 in.
3,852 photographs: color transparencies; 35 mm
24 photographs: prints, black and white; various sizes
2 portfolios (36 photographs): gelatin silver prints on card mounts, black and white; 13 x 15 in.
2 portfolios (29 photographs): gelatin silver prints on card mounts, black and white; 15 x 18 in.
5 portfolios (121 photographs): Ultrachrome archival inkjet prints, color; 19 x 13 in.
1 portfolio (14 photographs): gelatin silver prints on card mounts, sepia; 16 x 20 in.
1 portfolio (18 photographs): prints with original writing above and below with 2 prints on each card mount; 17 x 12 in.
1 portfolio (14 photographs): gelatin silver prints, black and white; 8 x 10 in.
4 portfolios (111 photographs): Ultrachrome archival inkjet prints, black and white; 19 x 13 in.
5,559 still image files: digital, jpg
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Photographs, writings, films, and ephemera comprising the professional archive of photographer Susan Caperna Lloyd. Includes documentation, mainly through photography and film, of Catholic Holy Week religious ritual as well as ethnographic documentation of folk traditions from around the world.
Provenance
Susan Caperna Lloyd; Purchase; 2018, 2020.
Accruals
No further accruals expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Susan Caperna Lloyd collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Susan Caperna Lloyd is an author, photographer, and filmmaker. She holds an Master of Fine Arts degree from the University of Oregon and her work incorporates elements of folklife, ethnography, religious studies, and anthropology.
Scope and Content
The collection documents Lloyd's expansive and varied career as an author, photographer, and filmmaker documenting folk rituals and customs around the world. A large portion of the collection focuses on Catholic Holy Week and Easter time folk religious rituals in the Philippines, Italy, Spain, New Mexico, Guatemala, and Mexico. Primarily through photographs, Lloyd recorded the adaptation of Catholic Holy Week rituals to include local folk customs. In addition to materials related to Holy Week folk rituals, Lloyd's work contains ethnographic documentation in the form of photographs, films, and writings from North, Central, and South America, Europe, Asia, and Africa regarding festivals, foodways, music, dance, anti-nuclear activism, Basque, Roma, Native American, and Latinx cultures. The collection includes journals and photographs from the entirety of Lloyd's career, beginning with her early work as a photographer and including her many research trips over the years. The production of Lloyd's documentary films, including The Last Zapatista, Processione: A Sicilian Easter, and The Baggage, are represented in the collection through film footage and production files. The descriptions found in this finding aid of material in the collection were provided by the donor, Susan Caperna Lloyd.
Arrangement
The Susan Caperna Lloyd collection is organized in 18 series according to major projects in Lloyd's career. Materials are arranged chronologically within each series.
Series 1: Academic, personal, and professional files (1961-1998)
Series 2: Early photographic work (1972-1986)
Series 3: Mexico (1971-2002, 2018, bulk: 1972-2002, 2018)
Series 4: Ecuador and Peru (1977-1978)
Series 5: Southwest United States (1978-2004, 2012)
Series 6: France and England (1978-1986, 2001-2002, 2012)
Series 7: Holy Week religious ritual (1978-2020)
Series 8: Oregon (1978-1991, 2020)
Series 9: Italian heritage and Italy (1978-2020)
Series 10: South Africa (1984-1987)
Series 11: Japan (1987-1994)
Series 12: Basque culture (1968-1998, bulk: 1989-1998)
Series 13: Cuba (1998-2004)
Series 14: Afghanistan (2005-2006)
Series 15: Turkey (2006)
Series 16: Kali folklore (1960, 1980, 2005, 2012-2014, bulk: 2012-2014)
Series 17: India (2014)
Series 18: Other folklife projects (1977-2014)
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Castillo Morales, Juan, -1938.; Lloyd, Susan Caperna, collector, creator.; Lloyd, Susan Caperna--Archives.; Lloyd, Susan Caperna--Correspondence.; Zapata, Emiliano, 1879-1919.
Organizations
Ejército Zapatista de Liberación Nacional (Mexico)
Subjects
All Souls' Day.; Antinuclear movement.; Basque Americans--Social life and customs.; Catholics--Italy.; Catholics--Mexico.; Catholics--Spain.; Crucifixion.; Folk religion.; Holy Week--Rites and ceremonies.; Italian American families--Biography.; Mayas--Religion.; Modoc Indians.; Navajo Indians--Social life and customs.; Processions, Religious.; Pueblo dance--New Mexico.; Tarahumara Indians--Rites and ceremonies.; Yaqui Indians--Arizona.; Yaqui Indians--Religion.
Places
Afghanistan--Social life and customs.; Cuba--Social life and customs.; Ecuador--Social life and customs.; England--Social life and customs.; France--Social life and customs.; Guatemala--Religious life and customs.; India--Religious life and customs.; India--Social life and customs.; Japan--Religious life and customs.; Mexico--Folklore.; Mexico--Religious life and customs.; Mexico--Social life and customs.; New Mexico--Religious life and customs.; New Mexico--Social life and customs.; Oregon--Social life and customs.; Peru--Social life and customs.; Philippines--Religious life and customs.; South Africa--Social life and customs.; Turkey--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Academic, personal, and professional files
  - Girl Scouts, Medford, Oregon, 1961, Girl Scout cross country hike journal/camp songs/sketches, southern Oregon.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/2)
  - Miscellaneous writings, 1961-1994, 1 folder (Box/folder 35/3)
    - Poems and other writings; Dreams, 1961-1984, 1961-1965 poems and other writings by Lloyd from a creative writing workshop at Jackson County Committee for the Study of Able and Gifted Children that Lloyd was selected to attend. Dreams, 1978-1984. Themes reflect Lloyd's formative years as she struggled to maintain her art while being dedicated to motherhood and raising her two sons.; AFC 2018/064: ZZ-01
    - Poems, 1963-1994, Themes range from Lloyd's high school imitation of Bob Dylan's song lyrics to later reflections on motherhood and its impact on her art.; AFC 2018/064: ZZ-02
  - Creative writing workshop, Southern Oregon University (1 of 2), 1964, Folder containing poems and writings by Susan (Caperna) Lloyd composed at Jackson County Committee for the Study of Gifted and Able Children's workshop at Southern Oregon University, winter, 1964. Lloyd was selected to attend this course while still in high school. Also includes the anthology of the class writings, including Lloyd's.; 1 binder (Box/folder 35/4)
  - Creative writing workshop, Southern Oregon University (2 of 2), 1964, Folder containing poems and writings by Susan (Caperna) Lloyd composed at Jackson County Committee for the Study of Gifted and Able Children's workshop at Southern Oregon University, winter, 1964. Lloyd was selected to attended this course while still in high school. Also includes the anthology of the class writings, including Lloyd's.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/5)
  - Drawings and sketches, 1965-1970, University of Oregon art classes.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/6)
  - Freemesser photography workshop, 1973-1974, First photography workshop, Bernard Freemesser's summer traveling workshop through the west, summer 1973. Trip with mother, Gail Caperna, 1974.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/7)
  - Dreams, 1974-1977, Record of dreams during MFA program, University of Oregon.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/8)
  - Basic Design - Color Theory notebook, 1975-1976, Robert Kostka, professor, MFA program, University of Oregon.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/9)
  - History of Photography courses, 1975-1977, Bernard Freemesser, professor, MFA program, University of Oregon.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/10)
  - MFA journal, 1975-1978, Professor Kostka, MFA program, University of Oregon. Observations on art, reviews, inspirations, notes from Bob Kostka's Basic Design classes.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 35/11)
  - History of Photography notebook, 1976, Bernard Freemesser, Professor, MFA program, University of Oregon.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 36/1)
  - History of Photography notebook, 1977, Bernard Freemesser, Professor, MFA program, University of Oregon.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 36/2)
  - Susan Lloyd photography workshops, 1977-1978, Posters advertising photography workshops in which Susan Lloyd taught: Oregon Photography Workshop, Eugene, Oregon, summer 1977; Northwest Artists Workshop, Portland, Oregon, August 18-27, 1978; Aesthetics of Photography, Portland, Oregon, August 2-8, 1978.; 1 folder (Box/folder 41/4)
  - Susan Lloyd photography exhibitions, 1977-2010, Miscellaneous Susan Lloyd photography exhibition announcements in the U.S., England, and Italy.; 1 folder (Box/folder 41/5)
  - Latin American Art History, University of Oregon course, MFA program, 1978, 1 notebook (Box/folder 36/3)
  - Personal journal and dreams, 1978-1982, Record of struggle to make personal experience visual through photography and themes of light, religion, birth/death; third trip to Mexico while pregnant, dreams, balancing motherhood and photography career in isolation in California after MFA program, University of Oregon. First serious documentation of people and use of writing with photographs through Portfolio 2: Sequences/Self-Portraits and Portfolio 3: Copy Photographs using old family pictures, interview with photographer Frederick Sommer, Prescott, Arizona.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 36/4)
  - Southern Oregon University, Ashland, Oregon workshops with Professor Don Kay (Photoshop), 1998, First experiments with Photoshop with Don Kay. First writings about how to incorporate digital ideas into photography.; 1 folder (Box/folder 36/5)
  - [Susan Lloyd's professional portfolio], undated, 1 folder (Box/folder 36/6)
- Series 2: Early photographic work
  Portfolios and negatives from Lloyd's early work as a photographer. Features photographs from her early world travels.
  - Early work, 1972-1978
    - Susan Lloyd with 4x5 camera, 1974, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-01 – SL-4x5-02; 2 black-and-white negatives (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Susan Lloyd self portrait, 1974-1976, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-03 – SL-4x5-04; 2 black-and-white negatives (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Cloud reflections in puddle, 1976, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-05; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch); Portfolio 1, Print 1 (Box 23)
    - Tom, 1976, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-06; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch); Portfolio 1, Print 16 (Box 23)
    - Deschutes River rocks, 1972, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-07; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch); Portfolio 1, Print 2 (Box 23)
    - Sand patterns, 1976, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-08; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch); Portfolio 1, Print 3 (Box 23)
    - Tom's hands, 1976, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-09; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch); Portfolio 1, Print 18 (Box 23)
    - Salida Coca-Cola Bottling Company, 1972, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-10; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Idaho World Building, 1972, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-11; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Pierre County Court House, 1972, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-12; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Christ Nazareno santo, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-13; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Santa Rosalia santo, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-14; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Sofa display, 1974, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-15; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Victorian eyelid window, 1972, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-16; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - White house ruins, Canyon de Chelly, 1973, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-17 – SL-4x5-19; 3 black-and-white negatives (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Butte, Montana, 1972, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-20; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
    - Sand patterns, 1976, AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-21; 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 inch) (Box 23)
  - Portfolio 1: Early Work, 1972-1983, The photographs in this portfolio of silver prints were made during Susan Lloyd's graduate school days in the Master of Fine Arts program at the University of Oregon, 1975-1978. Using a 2.25 x 2.25 inch Rolleiflex twin lens reflex camera, a 2.25 x 2.75 inch view camera, and a 4 x 5 inch Calumet view camera, her photographs strive for rich tonality from black to white and utilize the zone system of negative exposure and printing popularized by Ansel Adams and Edward Weston; as well, Lloyd mixed her own print developer, using Edward Weston's Amidol formula. Photographing with a tripod because of the view cameras, Lloyd sought still subjects. She focused always on natural light that revealed a subject's innermost nature. Her interest in a deeper revelation of character in the people she photographed led to her conversion to documentary photography several years later.; 1 portfolio (19 photographs): gelatin silver prints on card mount, black and white; 13 x 15 inch (Box 43)
    - Print 1: Cloud reflections in puddle, 1976, Eugene, Oregon street scene.; AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-05
    - Print 2: Deschutes River rocks, 1972, Scene on Deschutes River near Tumalo, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-07
    - Print 3: Sand patterns, 1976, Beach scene Pacific coast, Florence, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-08
    - Print 4: Chan Chan, Peru, 1977, Adobe ruins.; AFC 2018/064: SL-04-01
    - Print 5: Ayacucho, Peru, 1977, Adobe wall ruins.; AFC 2018/064: SL-05-04
    - Print 6: Erika, 1978, Erika with cross, Eugene, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-02-02
    - Print 7: Erika, 1978, Erika's hands, Eugene, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-02-02
    - Print 8: Motel cactus, 1977, Cactus in Tucson, Arizona, motel garden.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-13
    - Print 9: Tom in hallway, 1978, Rome, Italy hotel.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-10
    - Print 10: Angela's bedroom, 1977, Childhood bedroom of Angela Caperna, sister of photographer Susan Lloyd, Medford, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-06
    - Print 11: Tom in hat on bed, 1977, Portland, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-08
    - Print 12: Boat, 1976, Drydock, Florence, Oregon.
    - Print 13: San Xavier Mission, 1977, Tucson, Arizona.; AFC 2018/064: SL-01-03
    - Print 14: Mosaic, 1983, Mosaic and angel, Enna, Sicily.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-01
    - Print 15: Angela, 1977, Eugene, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-05
    - Print 16: Tom, 1976, Tom Lloyd, husband of photographer Susan Lloyd, Eugene, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-06
    - Print 17: Tom's back, 1976, Tom Lloyd, husband of photographer Susan Lloyd, Eugene, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-02
    - Print 18: Tom's hands, 1976, Tom Lloyd, husband of photographer Susan Lloyd, Eugene, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-4x5-09
    - Print 19: Michael, 1978, Michael Besh, friend and member of photography program at University of Oregon, Eugene, Oregon.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-15
    - Print 20: British Museum, 1978, London, England 1978.; AFC 2018/064: SL-26-14
  - Early work medium format, 1974, AFC 2018/064: SL-27-01; 7 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Susan with view camera; Kodak (Box 23)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-27], 1 folder (Box/folder 38/7)
  - Artists: Ruth Bernhard, Jerry Robinson, Bob Kostka, 1974-1985, AFC 2018/064: SL-25-01 – SL-25-03; 26 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); SL-25-01: Jerry Robinson, photographer; SL-25-02: Ruth Bernhard, San Francisco at her studio; SL-25-03: Bob Kostka, artist; Complete.; Kodak (Box 22)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-25], 1 folder (Box/folder 38/5)
  - Early work medium format, 1976-1986
    - Sicily, mosaic, 1983, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-01; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 14; Ilford (Box 22)
    - Tom's back, 1976, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-02; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 17; Ilford (Box 22)
    - Cesira Caperna, Veroli, Italy, 1983, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-03; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Kodak (Box 22)
    - Belle with eyes closed, Pendleton, Oregon, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-04; 2 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Kodak (Box 22)
    - Angela, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-05; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 15; Kodak (Box 22)
    - Angela's bedroom, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-06; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 10; Ilford (Box 22)
    - Tom on bed, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-07; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Kodak (Box 22)
    - Tom in hat on bed, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-08; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 11; Kodak (Box 22)
    - Sky in poncho, Santa Fe, New Mexico, 1986, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-09; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Kodak (Box 22)
    - Tom in hallway, Rome, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-10; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 9; Kodak (Box 22)
    - Saguaro cactus, Tucson, Arizona, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-11; 1 black-and-white negatives (120 mm) (Box 22)
    - Tarp (covering tractor), 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-12; 2 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Kodak (Box 22)
    - Motel cactus, Tucson, Arizona, 1977, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-13; 3 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Ilford (Box 22)
    - British Museum Sphinx, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-14; 3 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 20; Ilford (Box 22)
    - Michael Besh, 1978, AFC 2018/064: SL-26-15; 12 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); Portfolio 1, Print 19; Kodak (Box 22)
    - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-26], 1 folder (Box/folder 38/6)
  - [Exhibitions of early photographic work], 1978-1982, 1 folder (Box/folder 24/1)
  - Portfolio 2: Sequences/Self-Portraits, 1979-1982, This portfolio of Sequences/Self-Portraits were made from 1979-1982, before the time of "Selfies" popularized much later with the advent of digital cameras. They came into being because of a need to understand my changing self when I became pregnant at age thirty-two. The use of multiple imagery expressed what one image could not and was also a filmic idea. I found the self-portrait to be invaluable in really "seeing" myself and my growing child. The frames of each sequence were made in order in the camera on negative film, and occurred together "in sequence." They were then printed as a whole, so there was no cutting or manipulation. I also developed the use of words to accompany the images, feeling that the sequences were much like poems, each image in the sequence a word-picture and part of a greater whole which was, in itself, part of something else even greater. The use of writing longer captions with these sequences led to my eventual development as an author with continued pursuits in photography and film.; 1 portfolio (15 photographs): black-and-white gelatin silver prints on card mounts; 15 x 18 inch (Box 44)
    - Print 1: To find room in a room of one's own, June 1979
    - Print 2: In this journey we are alone, June 1979
    - Print 3: Chod - When the holy Milarepa finds the body of his dead mother he lies on it for three days to overcome his fears of it (Buddhist text), March 1980
    - Print 4: When we arrived in Albuquerque we truly had left home, July 1980
    - Print 5: Mothers, children, March 1980
    - Print 6: I had another falling off the mountain dream last night, February 1980
    - Print 7: As I have given birth to you, so have you to me, July 1980
    - Print 8: Dog mask, man and dog, August 1980
    - Print 9: The child makes the Zen garden, August 1980
    - Print 10: The proper use for tools: for Gary Snyder (setting out to learn that which is already known), January 1981
    - Print 11: We can perceive through our child's play whatever that is standing between us and greater happiness, March 1981
    - Print 12: For Bob Kostka, who understands children's marks, April 1981
    - Print 13: I think you're dancing right away from me, June 1982
    - Print 14: I was so protective of my Zen garden until you came along and threw a wrench into it. But actually I see that you have placed it well, June 1982
    - Print 15: The role of the artist is to free the reality manifested in a thing so that others can see, July 1982
    - Sequences/Self Portraits, 1979-1982, AFC 2018/064: SL-33-01; 49 black-and-white negatives (35 mm) (Box 23)
  - Portfolio 3: Copy Photographs/Journal Excerpts, 1981-1983, Prints 1-7 consist of a selection of old family snapshots recopied on a copy stand then printed (including the grid upon which they were placed) on sheets of photographic paper. By using the grid, I wanted to show that the snapshots were, indeed, "copied." I sepia-toned the old snapshots on the print, suggesting that they existed in the past, and left room underneath the printed photograph in which to write a text. These writings were invoked by studying the completed photographs, for they brought up old family memories. They are an outgrowth of my Sequences and my first use of extended writing with photographs. These "Copy Photographs" represent another need to understand how we view ourselves and our children. Since we are all someone's child and possibly someone's parent, the cycle is endless. Old family snapshots can provide clues in unraveling the mysteries of family life. Photographs 8-14, the "Journal Excerpts," utilize written text and photographic fragments, made from a journal kept in Italy during 1983. I traveled there with my husband and young son after receiving a grant from the Oregon Arts Commission to document my family heritage in and around the towns where my Italian father had lived before migrating to the U.S. in 1922.; 1 portfolio (14 photographs): black-and-white gelatin silver prints on card mounts; 15 x 18 inch (Box 45)
    - Print 1: Copy photograph #14: Dad, me, mother, Astoria (1953), 1981
    - Print 2: Copy photograph #8: Myself, age five, and dad, New Jersey (1952), 1982
    - Print 3: Copy photograph #16: Angela, myself, Shawn, seaside (1956), 1982
    - Print 4: Copy photograph #17: Shawn, Angela, myself (1961), 1982
    - Print 5: Copy photograph #19: Grandma Carolina, mother, Gary (1966), 1983
    - Print 6: Copy photograph #21A: Grandma Carolina, Gary (two months), mother (1961), 1983
    - Print 7: Copy photograph #21B: Ron, Gary (two months) and Gino Caperna (1961), 1983
    - Print 8: Abbey of St. Thomas Aquinas, Fossanova (1983), 1983
    - Print 9: Cesira Caperna, Veroli, Italy (1983), 1983
    - Print 10: Grandma Carolina, Amelia, dad, Gino, Rome (1926), 1926
    - Print 11: Rosaria's bedroom shrine to her dead husband, Terracina (1983), 1983
    - Print 12: Mannequin, Sicily (1983), 1983
    - Print 13: World War I monument with names of relatives, Veroli (1983), 1983